New England Medical Center Records MS099
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Publications, 1949 -- 1997; MS099.016; 8.4 Linear Feet
  - NEMC Finance, budget, 1984 -- 1985; MS099.016.291.00021 (Box 291)
  - Transition Systems, Inc., 1986 -- 1988; MS099.016.291.00022 (Box 291)
  - Transitions (T.S.-1), 1987; MS099.016.292.00001 (Box 292)
  - NEMCH News, 1987; MS099.016.292.00002 (Box 292)
  - NEMCH News, 1986; MS099.016.292.00003 (Box 292)
  - NEMCH Employee Council, 1988; MS099.016.292.00004 (Box 292)
  - NEMC Employees of NEMCH, 1975; MS099.016.292.00005 (Box 292)
  - NEMC Environmental Services, 1988; MS099.016.292.00006 (Box 292)
  - NEMC Epidemiology, 1985; MS099.016.292.00007 (Box 292)
  - Ethics committee, 1987; MS099.016.292.00008 (Box 292)
  - Finance, general, 1986 -- 1990; MS099.016.292.00009 (Box 292)
  - Finance, patient accounts, 1984 -- 1989; MS099.016.292.00010 (Box 292)
  - Finance, payroll, 1986 -- 1990; MS099.016.292.00011 (Box 292)
  - NEMCH News, 1987; MS099.016.292.00012 (Box 292)
  - NEMCH Department of Surgery annual reports, 1970 -- 1990; MS099.016.292.00013 (Box 292)
  - NEMC South Cove Community Health Center, 1985 -- 1986; MS099.016.292.00014 (Box 292)
  - Social Work Services, 1987 -- 1989; MS099.016.292.00015 (Box 292)
  - Safety and security, 1989; MS099.016.292.00016 (Box 292)
  - Department of Respiratory, 1987 -- 1989; MS099.016.292.00017 (Box 292)
  - NEMCH house staff manuals, 1982 -- 1986; MS099.016.292.00018 (Box 292)
  - TNEMC Educational Media Center, 1983; MS099.016.292.00019 (Box 292)
  - NEMCH News, 1990; MS099.016.292.00020 (Box 292)
  - NEMCH News, 1989; MS099.016.292.00021 (Box 292)
  - NEMCH News, 1988; MS099.016.292.00022 (Box 292)
  - NEMCH News, 1988; MS099.016.292.00023 (Box 292)
  - NEMC Department of Pediatrics, 1982 -- 1986; MS099.016.292.00024 (Box 292)
  - Pediatrics, 1985 -- 1989; MS099.016.292.00025 (Box 292)
  - Pediatrics, training programs, 1988 -- 1989; MS099.016.292.00026 (Box 292)
  - Pediatrics, Center for Genetic Counseling and Birth Defects Evaluation, 1985; MS099.016.292.00027 (Box 292)
  - Pediatrics, Hematology/Oncology, 1980 -- 1990; MS099.016.292.00028 (Box 292)
  - NEMC physical plant operation, 1989; MS099.016.292.00029 (Box 292)
  - NEMC Planning Office, 1984; MS099.016.292.00030 (Box 292)
  - Pratt Medical Group, Inc., 1986; MS099.016.292.00031 (Box 292)
  - NEMC Department of Psychiatry, general/adult, 1986 -- 1989; MS099.016.292.00032 (Box 292)
  - Pharmacy, 1988 -- 1990; MS099.016.292.00033 (Box 292)
  - Psychiatry Training Program, 1982 -- 1990; MS099.016.292.00034 (Box 292)
  - NEMC Department of Psychiatry, child, 1985 -- 1987; MS099.016.293.00001 (Box 293)
  - Hot Off the Press, 1993; MS099.016.293.00002 (Box 293)
  - Hot Off the Press, 1992; MS099.016.293.00003 (Box 293)
  - Women's Resource Center, 1980 -- 1990; MS099.016.293.00004 (Box 293)
  - Department of Public Relations, 1965 -- 1973; MS099.016.293.00005 (Box 293)
  - Quality assessment, 1990; MS099.016.293.00006 (Box 293)
  - NEMC Quality Assurance Utilization Program, 1984 -- 1989; MS099.016.293.00007 (Box 293)
  - NEMC Radiation/Oncology, general, 1984 -- 1988; MS099.016.293.00008 (Box 293)
  - Radiation/Oncology, health physics, 1987 -- 1990; MS099.016.293.00009 (Box 293)
  - NEMC Department of Radiology, 1987 -- 1990; MS099.016.293.00010 (Box 293)
  - NEMC Rehabilitation, 1970 -- 1989; MS099.016.293.00011 (Box 293)
  - Rehabilitation Institute, 1987 -- 1989; MS099.016.293.00012 (Box 293)
  - Research Administration, 1985 -- 1988; MS099.016.293.00013 (Box 293)
  - T-NEMC Department of Parking Services, 1984 -- 1988; MS099.016.293.00014 (Box 293)
  - NEMC Pathology - Clinical, memoranda, 1984 -- 1990; MS099.016.293.00015 (Box 293)
  - NEMC Pathology, manuals, 1980 -- 1985; MS099.016.293.00016 (Box 293)
  - Ophthalmology, 1986 -- 1989; MS099.016.293.00017 (Box 293)
  - Orthopedic Surgery - Sports and Medicinal Clinic, 1982 -- 1990; MS099.016.293.00018 (Box 293)
  - Otolaryngology, 1988 -- 1989; MS099.016.293.00019 (Box 293)
  - Nursing, performance appraisal forms, 1980 -- 1990; MS099.016.293.00020 (Box 293)
  - Nursing, patient units, 1984 -- 1988; MS099.016.293.00021 (Box 293)
  - Nursing newsletters, 1983 -- 1985; MS099.016.293.00022 (Box 293)
  - Nursing, job descriptions, 1989; MS099.016.293.00023 (Box 293)
  - Nursing Education Office, training materials, 1983 -- 1987; MS099.016.293.00024 (Box 293)
  - Nursing, Center for Case Management, conferences, 1987; MS099.016.293.00025 (Box 293)
  - Nursing, conferences, 1985; MS099.016.293.00026 (Box 293)
  - Nursing Education Office, orientation manuals, 1988; MS099.016.294.00001 (Box 294)
  - NEMC Departments of Obstetrics and Gynecology, 1984 -- 1989; MS099.016.294.00002 (Box 294)
  - Nursing, recruitment office, 1982 -- 1989; MS099.016.294.00003 (Box 294)
  - Nursing, policies and procedures, 1985 -- 1990; MS099.016.294.00004 (Box 294)
  - Nursing, policies and procedures, patient education syllabi, 1985 -- 1986; MS099.016.294.00005 (Box 294)
  - Nursing, general memoranda, 1985 -- 1989; MS099.016.294.00006 (Box 294)
  - Nursing Education Office, training materials, 1988 -- 1990; MS099.016.294.00007 (Box 294)
  - Nursing, conferences, 1983 -- 1984; MS099.016.294.00008 (Box 294)
  - Nursing Center for Case Management, training materials, 1985 -- 1986; MS099.016.294.00009 (Box 294)
  - Nursing Education Office, program schedules, 1984 -- 1989; MS099.016.294.00010 (Box 294)
  - Nursing, conferences, 1989; MS099.016.294.00011 (Box 294)
  - Nursing conferences, 1986 -- 1988; MS099.016.294.00012 (Box 294)
  - NEMCH News, 1972; MS099.016.313.00001 (Box 313)
  - NEMCH News, 1975 -- 1980; MS099.016.313.00002 (Box 313)
  - NEMCH News, 1981 -- 1982; MS099.016.313.00003 (Box 313)
  - NEMCH News, 1983 -- 1984; MS099.016.313.00004 (Box 313)
  - NEMCH News, 1984 -- 1985; MS099.016.313.00005 (Box 313)
  - NEMCH News, 1986; MS099.016.313.00006 (Box 313)
  - NEMC News, 1949 -- 1957; MS099.016.313.00007 (Box 313)
  - News Digest, 1978; MS099.016.313.00008 (Box 313)
  - News Digest, 1979; MS099.016.313.00009 (Box 313)
  - News Digest, 1981; MS099.016.313.00010 (Box 313)
  - In-Crowd, 1969; MS099.016.313.00011 (Box 313)
  - In-Crowd, 1970; MS099.016.313.00012 (Box 313)
  - In-Crowd, 1971; MS099.016.313.00013 (Box 313)
  - In-Crowd, 1972; MS099.016.313.00014 (Box 313)
  - In-Crowd, 1973; MS099.016.313.00015 (Box 313)
  - In-Crowd, 1974; MS099.016.313.00016 (Box 313)
  - Volunteer, The, 1965 -- 1982; MS099.016.313.00017 (Box 313)
  - In the News, 1986 -- 1987; MS099.016.313.00018 (Box 313)
  - The News in Review, 1985; MS099.016.313.00019 (Box 313)
  - The Year in Review, 1984 -- 1987; MS099.016.313.00020 (Box 313)
  - Update, 1979 -- 1982; MS099.016.313.00021 (Box 313)
  - Dimensions, 1971 -- 1980; MS099.016.313.00022 (Box 313)
  - T-NEMC Report, 1970 -- 1971; MS099.016.313.00023 (Box 313)
  - Around NEMC, 1978 -- 1982; MS099.016.313.00024 (Box 313)
  - On Center, 1970; MS099.016.313.00025 (Box 313)
  - News clippings, 1997; MS099.016.313.00026 (Box 313)
- Oversized material and artifacts, 1948 -- 1990; MS099.017; 14.4 Linear Feet
  This series contains scrapbooks, images, and artifacts made by or on behalf of NEMC. Scrapbooks represent press material spanning the late 1950s, and artifacts are items made for NEMC fundraising functions. Also included in this series is Frances Stern's diploma.
  - Frances Stern Nutrition Center poster, MS099.017.297.00001 (Box 297)
  - Press clippings, 1954 -- 1956; MS099.017.298.00001 (Box 298)
  - Press clippings, 1955 -- 1957; MS099.017.298.00002 (Box 298)
  - Press clippings, 1958 -- 1960; MS099.017.298.00003 (Box 298)
  - Press clippings, 1961 -- 1962; MS099.017.298.00004 (Box 298)
  - New England Center Hospital staff, 1968; MS099.017.299.00001 (Box 299)
  - PC/NECH - portrait of Dr. George B. Farnsworth, 1968; MS099.017.299.00002 (Box 299)
  - PC/NECH - Planning Department drawings, 1948; MS099.017.299.00003 (Box 299)
  - PC/NECH - Staff, Medicine and Neurology departments, 1960 -- 1968; MS099.017.299.00004 (Box 299)
  - PC/NECH - Planning office, 1960 -- 1980; MS099.017.299.00005 (Box 299)
  - 193-205 Harrison avenue and 1-17 Nassau street, 1960 -- 1980; MS099.017.299.00006 (Box 299)
  - PC/NECH - group portrait of house officers, 1949 -- 1962; MS099.017.299.00007 (Box 299)
  - Places. Streets. Washington., MS099.017.299.00008 (Box 299)
  - Joseph Pratt portrait, MS099.017.299.00009 (Box 299)
  - Drawing of Jackson Memorial Building of the Boston Floating Hospital, MS099.017.299.00010 (Box 299)
  - TUSM medical education building proposals illustrations, 1961 -- 1971; MS099.017.299.00011 (Box 299)
  - T-NEMC Planning Office - transparencies, Planning illustrations, MS099.017.299.00012 (Box 299)
  - Samuel Rogers visual materials, 1961; MS099.017.299.00013 (Box 299)
  - Poster to benefit BFH Building Fund, MS099.017.299.00014 (Box 299)
  - NEMC sponsorship certificate from Michael Dukakis, 1986-10-11; MS099.017.300.00001 (Box 300)
  - Portraits of Frances Stern and unidentified woman, MS099.017.300.00002 (Box 300)
  - Frances Stern diploma, MS099.017.300.00003 (Box 300)
  - Samuel Proger certificates, 1952-04-01 -- 1954-05-17; MS099.017.300.00004 (Box 300)
  - "Launch the Floating" button, 1980; MS099.017.303.00001 (Box 303)
    Campaign button used in the Floating Hospital Building Fund Drive.
  - "The Bottom Line" button, 1984; MS099.017.303.00002 (Box 303)
    Campaign button used in Management Project's Expo '84 Exhibition.
  - "We Are New England Medical Center" button, 1986; MS099.017.303.00003 (Box 303)
    Quality control campaign button prepared by Human Resources.
  - "My jestesmy Osrodek Medyczny New England" button, 1986; MS099.017.303.00004 (Box 303)
    Polish language
  - "We Are the New England Medical Center" button, 1986; MS099.017.303.00005 (Box 303)
    Chinese characters
  - "Chung toi la Trung Tam Y-khoa cua Tan Anh-Cat-Loi" button, 1986; MS099.017.303.00006 (Box 303)
    Vietnamese language
  - "We Are New England Medical Center" button, 1986; MS099.017.303.00007 (Box 303)
    Greek language, Modern
  - "Somos del Centro Medico de Nueva Inglaterra" button, 1986; MS099.017.303.00008 (Box 303)
    Spanish language
  - NEMC Gallbusters Gallstone Treatment button, 1980 -- 1990; MS099.017.303.00009 (Box 303)
  - Ladies Committee gavel, 1980 -- 1990; MS099.017.303.00010 (Box 303)
  - Desktop embosser with seal of Boston Floating Hospital., 1965; MS099.017.303.00012 (Box 303)
  - Desktop embosser with seal of New England Center Hospital, MS099.017.303.00013 (Box 303)
- Archives of the New England Medical Center Hospitals records, 1986 -- 1990; MS099.018; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains research files on the evolution of NEMC, as well as histories for the institutions from which NEMC originated. Included in this series are articles, timelines, corporate histories, research notes compiled for future exhibits, and documentation for volunteer opportunities.
  This series is arranged at the container level.
  - Files of the Archives of the New England Medical Center Hospitals, 1986 -- 1990; MS099.018.314 (Box 314)
- Legacy collection documentation, 1990; MS099.019; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains the finding aids by NEMC archivist Dave Nathan, as well as NEMC acquisition records.
  - Legacy collection documentation folder, 1990; MS099.018.203.00013 (Box MS099 Shared 7)